Celebrate 30 years of The King of Pop!
Michael Jackson: 30th Anniversary Celebration is a music,
documentary film directed by Bruce Gowers.
The Michael Jackson: 30th Anniversary Special was a 2001
New York City revue show by Michael Jackson.
It took place on September 7, 2001 and September 10, 2001.
In late November 2001, the CBS television network aired the concerts as a two-hour special in honour of Michael Jackson's
thirtieth year as a solo entertainer (his first solo single, "Got to Be There", was recorded in 1971).
The show was edited from footage of two separate concerts Michael had orchestrated in New
York City's Madison Square Garden on September 7 and September 10 of 2001.
The shows sold out in five hours.
Ticket prices were pop's most expensive ever; the best seats cost $5,000 and
included a dinner with Michael Jackson and a signed poster.
Self, played by Michael Jackson.
Self, played by Muhammad Ali.
Self, played by Marc Anthony.
Self, played by Monica.
Self, played by Marlon Brando.
Self, played by Cyd Charisse.
Michael Joseph Jackson (August 29, 1958 – June 25, 2009) was an
American singer, songwriter, dancer, and philanthropist.
Dubbed the "King of Pop", he is widely regarded as one of the most
culturally significant figures of the 20th century.
Over a four-decade career, his musical achievements broke American
racial barriers and made him a dominant figure worldwide.
Through his songs, concerts, and fashion, he proliferated visual performance for artists in popular music,
popularizing street dance moves such as the moonwalk, the robot, and the anti-gravity lean.
Jackson is often deemed the greatest entertainer of all time.
The eighth child of the Jackson family, Michael made his public debut at age six as
the lead singer of the Jackson 5, one of Motown's most successful acts.
He rose to solo stardom with the album Off the Wall (1979) and achieved unprecedented
global success with Thriller (1982), the best-selling album in history.
Its short film-style music videos for "Thriller", "Beat It", and
"Billie Jean" redefined the medium as an art form.
Jackson followed it with Bad (1987), the first album to produce five US Billboard Hot 100 number-one singles: "I Just
Can't Stop Loving You", "Bad", "The Way You Make Me Feel", "Man in the Mirror", and "Dirty Diana".
His next two albums, Dangerous (1991) and HIStory (1995), explored socially
conscious themes while Invincible (2001) delved into more personal topics.
From the mid-1980s, Jackson came under public scrutiny due to changes in
his appearance, relationships, behavior, and lifestyle.
He was accused of sexually abusing the child of a family friend in 1993.
In 2005, Jackson was tried and acquitted of further
such allegations and other charges.
In 2009, while preparing for This Is It, a series of comeback concerts, he died from an overdose of propofol
administered by his personal physician Conrad Murray, who was convicted of involuntary manslaughter in 2011.
Jackson's death triggered global reactions, creating unprecedented
surges of internet traffic and a spike in his music sales.
His televised memorial service, held at the Staples Center in Los Angeles, is
estimated to have been viewed by more than 2.5 billion people.
Jackson is one of the best-selling music artists of all time,
with estimated sales of over 500 million records.
He holds a joint-record for a male solo artist with 13 Billboard Hot 100 number-one
singles and is the only artist to have a top-ten single in six decades.
One of the most-awarded music artists in history, Jackson received 13 Grammy Awards, the Grammy Legend Award, and the Grammy Lifetime Achievement
Award; 26 American Music Awards; 12 World Music Awards; eight MTV Video Music Awards; six Brit Awards; and three presidential honors.
He was inducted into numerous halls of fame, including the Rock and Roll Hall of
Fame twice, the Songwriters Hall of Fame, and the Dance Hall of Fame.
Having donated an estimated $500 million, Jackson is credited
with setting a standard for celebrity charity.
In 2024, half of his music catalogue was sold to Sony for $600
million, the largest music acquisition for a single artist.
The film explores themes of concert, pop, rock
music, live performance, pop music.